James Hoggard

Washington, DC 20003 | jameshoggard.dev@gmail.com

GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced full stack engineer with a strong passion for delivering innovative solutions. Mastery of React & Node, alongside high proficiency with Ruby on Rails reinforced by a background in detailed problem solving. Self-motivated team player. Excellent communication skills with a strong grasp of the importance of meeting goals and delivering a quality product in an agile environment. Deeply driven to work with teams that strive to confront modern issues and have a sincere dedication to diversity & inclusivity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), React, Ruby on Rails, Python, JSON, Linux, Mac, RESTful APIs, Next.js, PostgreSQL, Express, MySQL, SQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Reexpress - GitHub

View/add customer reviews for products/services.

- Built front end with React.js, Express/Node backend with API endpoints for Fetch requests.
- Followed multiple conventions of React's built-in hooks.

jSBattleship - GitHub

A game of strategy, action, and suspense.

- Used MVC framework to execute game design.
- Adhered to the single-responsibility principle and created custom methods to process game events.

HomePro - GitHub

Helps patients with their home exercise program after their facility stay or therapy treatment visits have concluded.

- Installed user authentication via Rails sessions and cookies, providing a secure web application for patients and therapists.
- Configured custom routes in Rails backend to allow seamless and secure user login and signup forms.
- Utilized React hooks to implement controlled forms for user login, sign-up, and event creation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intermediate JavaScript Engineer/Contractor

05/2022 - Current

05/2016

• Initializing/updating React based websites. Learning to operate MySQL databases as well as CMS independently. Signed NDA, not able to disclose employer.

Junior Software Engineer 2021

Flatiron School

Doctor of Physical Therapy (DPT)

• Built portfolio projects to demonstrate school based and non school based technical skills.

Physical TherapistMiami-Dade County, FLMedCare Home Health Services01/2020 - 02/2021

Conducted patient evaluations and documented outcomes for underserved individuals in the community.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolWashington, DCFull Stack Web Development, JavaScript & Ruby on Rails program02/2021 - 06/2021Hampton UniversityHampton, VA